var jsonData = [
  {
    "Question": "Why do customers needs vary?",
    "answer": "• Benefits they require  <br />• Amount of money they are able/willing to pay  <br />• Quantity of goods they require  <br />• Quality of goods they require  <br />• Time and location they wish to purchase the goods",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the 6 main types of market segmentation?",
    "answer": "• Age  <br />• Gender  <br />• Occupation  <br />• Income  <br />• Geographic  <br />• Lifestyle",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the benefits to a business of market segmentation?",
    "answer": "• Ensures customer needs are matched and met  <br />• Potential for increased profits/profitability  <br />• Increased customer retention  <br />• Allows for targeted marketing  <br />• Potential for an increase in market share",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the purposes to a business of conducting market research?",
    "answer": "• To reduce risk  <br />• To understand the market  <br />• To promote the organisation  <br />• To aid decision making  <br />• To gain customers’ views and understand their needs<br />• To inform product development",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main Primary (Field) Market Research methods",
    "answer": "• Observations  <br />• Questionnaires  <br />• Surveys  <br />• Focus groups  <br />• Consumer trials",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main Secondary (desk) Market Research Methods?",
    "answer": "• Internal data  <br />• Books/newspapers/trade magazines  <br />• Competitors’ data  <br />• Government publications and statistics  <br />• Purchased research material (e.g. Mintel)",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain WHY a business might face problems if the market is not segmented.",
    "answer": "If the market is not segmented the business will not have a clear target market. This will mean it does not  fully understand the customer’s needs, leading to difficulty in decision making. Therefore, it may not be  able to decide on suitable products, promotions, and pricing. This will lead to a lack of customers, making  it difficult to make sales.",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the 5 main benefits of market segmentation",
    "answer": "• Ensures customer needs are matched and met <br />• Potential for increased profits/profitability <br />• Increased customer retention <br />• Allows for targeted marketing <br />• Potential for an increase in market share",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 disadvantages of market segmentation",
    "answer": "• Research may be expensive <br />• Market too small <br />• Budgets may be limited",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 situations when market research is necessary",
    "answer": "• Setting up a new business <br />• Introducing new products to an existing business <br />• Responding to changes in consumers’ tastes",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 digital tools that might be used for Primary research",
    "answer": "• Social media <br />• Video conferencing <br />• Sensors",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain the difference between Qualitative data and Quantitative data",
    "answer": "Quantitative data is numeric e.g. average price a customer is willing to pay. It is easy to analyse.  Qualitative data is non-numeric. It gives more detailed information on opinions and reasons for  consumers behaviour.",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages of Primary Market research",
    "answer": "Specific to the needs of the business Up to date - new information",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 disadvantages of Primary Market Research",
    "answer": "Can be time consuming to carry out and can also be very expensive",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages of Secondary Market research",
    "answer": "Already collected so quick to access and is also cheap or free. May be from an expert source",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 disadvantages of Secondary Market Research",
    "answer": "General research rather than specific to the  business  <br />Sometimes have to pay for it – can be expensive",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What types of customer feedback techniques are available to a business start-up",
    "answer": "",
    "Topic": "LO1 - How to target a market",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Define Fixed Costs",
    "answer": "Costs that do not vary with the level of output",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Define Variable Costs",
    "answer": "Costs that do vary with the level of output",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Give some common examples of Fixed Costs",
    "answer": "rent<br />loan repayment<br />insurance<br />advertising<br />salaries<br />utilities",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Give some common examples of Variable Costs",
    "answer": "raw materials<br />components<br />stock<br />packaging",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "How do you calculate Total Costs?",
    "answer": "Total Costs=Fixed Costs + Variable Costs",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "How do you calculate Revenue from sales?",
    "answer": "Revenue=Selling Price x Number of units sold",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Define Break-even",
    "answer": "The level of output where total Revenue = Totals costs",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the break-even formula?",
    "answer": "Fixed Costs/(Selling price-Variable Cost)",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "How is profit calculated?",
    "answer": "Revenue - Total Costs",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "How is profit per unit calculated?",
    "answer": "Selling price per unit-total costs per unit",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why do businesses need to know the break-even point?",
    "answer": "They can work out how many units they need to sell to break even and then decide whether their business idea is viable, They can use the data to inform business decisions on selling price, The can use the data to help convince/persuade a potential investor/lender",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain why salaries are fixed costs and wages are variable costs",
    "answer": "Salaries are a fixed amount paid to managers regardless of the number of hours worked. Therefore, they  do not vary with output. Wages are paid according to the amount of work done and are therefore likely to  vary with output. As more output will mean more hours worked.",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A business sells 1 500 units, with fixed costs of £3 300 and variable cost per unit of £2.00.  Calculate the total costs.",
    "answer": "Fixed costs + variable costs <br />£3 300 + £3 000 = £6 300",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Total variable costs for a business that makes 400 bicycles is £20 000. <br />Calculate the variable cost per unit.",
    "answer": "£20 000 / 400 = £50 per bicycle",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A business sells 1 500 units, with a selling price of £5.00 per unit. <br />Calculate the total revenue.",
    "answer": "£5.00 x 1 500 = £7 500",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "The following data applies to a business. <br />• Fixed costs £2 000 per month; Variable costs £4.00 per unit; Selling price £7.50 per unit; Quantity sold 1 000 per month <br /><br />Calculate the total cost for the year<br />Calculate the total revenue for the year",
    "answer": "Total cost per year <br />FC = £2 000 x 12 = £24 000 <br />VC = £4.00 x (1 000 x 12) = £48 000 <br />TC = £24 000 + £48 000 = £72 000<br />Total revenue per year <br />£7.50 x (1 000 x 12) = £90 000",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A business sells 1 500 units, with a selling price of £5.00 per unit. Fixed costs are £3 300 and variable costs £2.00 per unit. Calculate the break-even point.",
    "answer": "Fixed cost/(Price – variable cost per unit) <br />£3 300/(£5.00 - £2.00) <br />= £3 300/£3.00 = 1 100 units",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain how and why a change in revenue affects the break even level of output",
    "answer": "If revenue increases, whilst costs remain the same, the break-even level of output will fall.",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain how and why a change in sosts affects the breakeven level of output",
    "answer": "If costs increase, whilst revenue remains the same, the break-even level of output will rise.",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A business sells 200 coat hangers at £0.50 per unit. Total costs are £50.  <br />Calculate the profit per unit.",
    "answer": "£0.50 – (£50/200) = £0.25",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "A business has a sales revenue of £45 000. Fixed costs are £15 000 and total variable costs are  £12 000. Calculate the profit.",
    "answer": "£45 000 – (£15 000 + £12 000) = £18 000",
    "Topic": "LO2 - What makes a product or service viable",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the 5 stages of the Product Life Cycle?",
    "answer": "• Development  <br />• Introduction  <br />• Growth  <br />• Maturity  <br />• Decline",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain what is happening in the business at the Development stage of the product life cycle",
    "answer": "• Sales are zero and the product is therefore not contributing to  revenue <br />• Spending on research and development is likely to be high",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain what is happening in the business at the Introduction stage of the product life cycle",
    "answer": "• Likely to be expensive as the enterprise advertises to raise awareness <br />• Sales could be slow to start which could lead to initial losses",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain what is happening in the business at the Growth stage of the product life cycle",
    "answer": "• Consumers become familiar with the product and repeat custom is  built up <br />• No longer needs to be promoted so heavily",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain what is happening in the business at the Maturity stage of the product life cycle",
    "answer": "• Competition may become stronger <br />• The product should now be contributing to the business’ profits",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain what is happening in the business at the Decline stage of the product life cycle",
    "answer": "• The firm will decide on either an extension strategy or discontinuing  the product <br />• Revenue will be low and falling",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain the 3 elements of the Design Mix Model",
    "answer": "1. The function is what the product does. If it not able to perform its basic function, then it is not fit for  purpose. For example, nobody would buy a kettle that does not boil water. <br />2. Aesthetics is the look and feel of the product. This makes it attractive to the customer. This can create  product differentiation as it adds value. <br />3. Cost is whether a business can produce it within a given budget. If costs are too high, then the business may have to set a high selling price that would make it non-competitive in the market,  leading to no sales.",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain WHY identifying a clear unique selling point (USP) helps a business to differentiate a product.",
    "answer": "A USP is a feature or function that only that product has. This makes it different from other products on  the market giving it a competitive advantage. Therefore, it stands out, showing that it has achieved  product differentiation.",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain, using an example, WHY a recession impacts on product development.",
    "answer": "During a recession consumers will have less disposable income. Demand will shift away from luxury goods  to ones that are seen as better value for money. Businesses will look to offer cheaper alternatives. They  may therefore develop a new product range to meet the needs of more price conscious consumers. For  example, in the 2008 recession Marks & Spencer’s introduced a range of £1 sandwiches.",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain, using an example, WHY a boom impacts on product development.",
    "answer": "Businesses will be confident meaning they are willing to invest in capital equipment or building new  facilities. This could lead to the introduction of new products onto the market. For example, car  manufacturers may increase output and launch new models of existing cars.",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain, using an example, WHY copyright and patents impact on product development",
    "answer": "Intellectual property such as patents and copyright protect business ideas from being copied by others.  This therefore helps the businesses recoup the cost of investment in R&D. James Dyson has a large range  of innovative products that are protected by patents allowing the business to charge high prices",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain, using an example, WHY product safety standards impact on product development",
    "answer": "Product safety standards may slow down product development as businesses will need to make sure new  products are thoroughly tested to ensure they meet the required standards. However, once launched this  will help the product be successful as it will be fit for purpose and meet the needs of the customer safely",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify and explain 5 possible Extensions strategies for products in the  product life cycle",
    "answer": "• Advertising  <br />• Price changes  <br />• Adding value (e.g. improving the specification of an existing  product)  <br />• Exploration of new markets (e.g. new geographic market,  new target markets)  <br />• New packaging",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify how a business can differentiate its products",
    "answer": "Establishing a strong brand image for goods or services<br />Design mix model  - i.e. the variables that contribute to successful product  design - function, cost and appearance<br />Identifying a clear unique selling point (USP)  <br />Offering improved:  <br />- Location  <br />- Features  <br />- Functions  <br />- Design  <br />- Appearance  <br />- Selling price",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain the 3 main external factors that can impact on product development in a company",
    "answer": "• Technological developments (e.g. developments in  technology that affect production capabilities and consumer  preferences)  <br />• Economic issues (i.e. recession, boom and their effects)  <br />• Legal issues (i.e. copyright and patent, product safety  standards)",
    "Topic": "LO3 - Product development",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What 3 factors must a company sonsider when pricing a product to attract and retain customers?",
    "answer": "• Income levels of target customers  <br />• Price of competitor products  <br />• Cost of production",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main types of pricing strategies that businesses tend to use when pricing their products?",
    "answer": "• Competitive pricing  <br />• Psychological pricing  <br />• Price skimming  <br />• Price penetration",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What types of advertising methods are used to attract and retain customers?",
    "answer": "• Leaflets  <br />• Social Media  <br />• Websites  <br />• Newspapers  <br />• Magazines  <br />• Radio",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What Sales Promotion techniques can a company use to attract and retain customers?",
    "answer": "• Discounts  <br />• Competitions  <br />• Buy one get one free (BOGOF)  <br />• Point of sale advertising  <br />• Free gifts/product trials  <br />• Loyalty schemes",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the 3 main methods of customer service that a business can use to attract and retain customers?",
    "answer": "• Product knowledge  <br />• Customer engagement (e.g. presentation, communication  skills)  <br />• After sales service",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using a Competitive pricing strategy",
    "answer": "Keeps the business competitive. Encourages the business to  focus on the product and promotions to attract  customers.<br />May lead to price wars if one business lowers their price.  Needs to be constantly  monitored.",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using a Psychological pricing strategy",
    "answer": "Helps the business to generate greater sales as product perceived to be in a lower price bracket e.g. £9.99. <br />Attracts customers who perceive  the product to be better value  for money.<br />Can be perceived as a ploy by  the business to rip-off the  customer. <br />Requires holding large amounts  of small change when  undertaking cash transactions.",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using a Price Skimming pricing strategy",
    "answer": "The business can quickly recoup  R&D costs. <br />Makes high revenue on early  sales, before the price is  lowered.<br />The business may not be  <br />competitive. <br />Brand image can be damaged if  the business is thought to be  exploiting customers who buy  first.",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using a Price Penetration pricing strategy",
    "answer": "Customers are encouraged to try  a new product which is seen as  value for money. <br />Low profit margins per good  sold.<br />Customers may stop buying and  go to competitors once price is  raised. <br />Early sales may not make  <br />sufficient profit.",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Leaflets for advertising",
    "answer": "• Relatively cheap to produce <br />• Easy to distribute<br />• May be ignored or seen as a nuisance <br />• Relatively small geographical area",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Social Media for advertising",
    "answer": "• A free source of advertising <br />• Reach a large geographical area<br />• Difficult to control negative comments <br />• Time consuming to maintain a high media presence",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Websites for advertising",
    "answer": "• Contain a large amount of  <br />information e.g. images and videos <br />• Reach a large geographical area<br />• Need to be regularly updated <br />• Can be expensive if produced  <br />professionally",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Newspapers for advertising",
    "answer": "• Easy to target to a specific market <br />• May include being featured on the newspaper’s website<br />• Often quickly thrown away <br />• Costs may be high",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Magazines for advertising",
    "answer": "• Easy to target to a specific market <br />• May include being featured on the magazine’s website<br />• Costs are likely to be high <br />• Likely to also feature adverts by  competitors",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Radio for advertising",
    "answer": "• Easy to target a specific <br />geographical area <br />• Can be frequently repeated to  reinforce the message<br />• Customers are unlikely to react on the  spot <br />• May be expensive to both produce and pay for airtime",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Discounts as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• Prompts an immediate action <br />• New customers may be more  willing to try a product at a cheaper  price<br />• Lower profit on each item sold • Customers may hold off buying a  product waiting for discounts to be  applied",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Competitions as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• May encourage multiple purchases  for the length of the competition <br />• Customers may have to buy the  product to enter the competition, increasing sales<br />• Prizes may be expensive to supply<br /> • Sales may fall again immediately  after the competition finishes",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using BOGOFs as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• Prompts an immediate action <br />• New customers may be more  willing to try a product<br />• Can be expensive for the business <br />• May reduce sales in the medium  term if regular customers do not  need to buy again because they have  “stocked up”",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Point of Sale advertising as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• Prompts an immediate action <br />• Sometimes includes samples to  encourage customers to buy a  product<br />• Can attract criticism <br />e.g. “pester power” <br />• Does not encourage repeat or  multiple purchases",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Freebies/Product trials as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• Gift may act as a frequent  <br />reminder of the brand to the  <br />customer <br />• May encourage customers to try a  new product to get the gift<br />• Increases the costs of the business <br />• The customer may not buy further products once they have the gift",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 2 advantages and disadvantages of using Loyalty schemes as a sales promotion technique",
    "answer": "• Encourages repeat purchases<br />• Builds brand loyalty<br />• Can be linked to collecting details about customers’ buying habits <br />• Customers may use multiple  loyalty schemes hence not increasing  loyalty",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain why customer service can help aimprove a business' performance",
    "answer": "Customer service can help a business gain a good reputation. This will lead to positive word of mouth  advertising as existing customers tell potential new customers about the quality of service received. This  will lead to new customers trying the business who in turn will become repeat customers. The  continuation of this cycle will help a business to grow. This growth will result in improved financial  performance through greater demand.",
    "Topic": "LO4 - How to attract and retain customers",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the main forms of ownership for start-up businesses",
    "answer": "• Sole trader  <br />• Partnership, including limited liability partnerships  <br />• Franchise",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main legal requirements of Sole Traders and Partnerships when starting up",
    "answer": "Must register themselves as self employed with HMRC",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What additional legal requirements are involved when setting up a LLP?",
    "answer": "Must send a Memorandum and Articles of Association to Companies House and receive a Certificate of Incorporation back before they can start trading",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is meant by unlimited liability?",
    "answer": "The owners are personally responbible for all of the company's debts and their personal assets could be at risk",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is meant by limited liability?",
    "answer": "Personal liability of the owners is limited only to the amount of money they invested into the company",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the 6 main sources of finance for a start-up business?",
    "answer": "• own savings  <br />• friends and family  <br />• loans  <br />• crowdfunding  <br />• small business grants  <br />• business angels",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Why are business plans so important?",
    "answer": "to clarify a business idea to others (e.g. to secure funding) <br />to measure progress towards goals (e.g. timescales, sales  forecasts)  <br /> to help manage cash flow  <br /> to help identify potential problems (e.g. financial shortages)",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 advantages to being a Sole Trader",
    "answer": "Cheap and easy to set up. <br />Keep all the profits for themselves. <br />Accounts are private and cannot be seen by  competitors.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 disadvantages to being a Sole Trader",
    "answer": "Unlimited liability. <br />Hard work. <br />Limited finance available.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 advantages to being a Partnership",
    "answer": "Risks and responsibilities shared. <br />Different skills and expertise. <br />Shared finance – each partner invests making it  easier to raise finance.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 disadvantages to being a Partnership",
    "answer": "Unlimited liability. <br />Disagreements can occur between partners. If a partner dies, resigns or goes bankrupt the  partnership is dissolved.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 advantages to being a Franchise",
    "answer": "Established brand name. <br />Help and advice from the franchisor in several  areas such as location and recruitment.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 disadvantages to being a Franchise",
    "answer": "Normally requires an initial cost to obtain the  franchise and ongoing costs to retain it. <br />Often requires raw materials to be brought from  the franchisee. <br />Strict rules apply as to how the franchisee can  operate.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 4 reasons why a business will need capital when starting up.",
    "answer": "• Buy stock <br />• Rent premises <br />• Advertise the opening <br />• Fixtures and fittings",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 4 reasons why additional finance may be required during the first few years of  operating a new business",
    "answer": "• Recruit employees <br />• Develop new products <br />• Solve cash flow problems <br />• Relocate to bigger premises",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using your own savings as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />No need to pay interest or repay finance. Retention of ownership by the individual.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Amount available limited to own savings. Puts stress on the day to day finance of the  individual such as paying a mortgage or monthly  bills.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using friends and family as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />There may be no need to pay interest. <br />May be an informal agreement.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Amount available may be limited. <br />Put strain on the relationship.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using loans as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />Relatively quick and easy to secure, especially for  established businesses with assets. <br />Fixed interest rates allow businesses to budget  more easily.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Interest must be paid regardless of profit levels. Often more expensive than other finance sources.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using crowdfunding as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />The business can use the internet to explain how  much money is required and how it will be used. It is a low cost and quick way of raising finance.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Often will fail to raise the finance required. Allows competitors to see ideas and valuable  information about the business.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using small business grants as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />Often linked to additional support.  <br />Do not need to repay.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Can be difficult to qualify.  <br />May incur additional requirements e.g. to relocate  in a specific area.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify the advantages and disadvantages of using business angels as a source of capital",
    "answer": "Advantages: <br />Potential for large sums of money for  <br />investment. <br />Expertise to help the business.<br />Disadvantages: <br />Expert financial projections are likely to be  required. <br />Partial loss of ownership due to giving away  equity.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Identify 3 individuals or groups who may want to see a business plan and why",
    "answer": "Investors <br />To gain an understanding of the business’ products and  potential to make a profit.<br />Employees <br />To identify whether this is the type of business they would like  to work for and whether it is able to offer them job security.<br />Supplier <br />To decide whether they are willing to offer the business trade  credit based on the financial forecasts.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain WHY a business plan is important in helping to meet sales forecasts.",
    "answer": "A business plan will set out projected sales levels for the first few years. These could be broken down into  monthly targets. These targets could help motivate an entrepreneur and employees.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain the benefits of demonstrating a healthy cash flow forecast when preparing a business plan.",
    "answer": "It is important to show a healthy cash flow forecast when preparing a business plan. This will be used by  investors to decide if they are willing to invest, suppliers to decide if they are willing to give credit and  employees to see if they trust the business.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain why having a Sales strategy in your business plan is important",
    "answer": "Target for amount of sales, by value or volume, to be met within given time frames. Allows the business  to motivate employees by setting individual targets. Progress can be checked, and action take if  necessary.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain why having a marketing strategy in your business plan is important",
    "answer": "Details of price, product, promotion and place. Acts as a guide for what the marketing department  should be doing on a day by day and medium-term basis e.g. what promotional techniques will be used  and when.",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "Explain why a business plan is important in securing funding",
    "answer": "It can often be difficult to obtain finance but having a comprehensive business plan will give potential  investors and banks more confidence in receiving a positive return as financial forecasts have been made,  which will encourage them to invest in the business",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What should a business plan contain?",
    "answer": "business objectives  <br />business strategies  <br />sales plan  <br />marketing plan  <br />financial forecasts",
    "Topic": "LO5 - Factors for consideration when starting up a business",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the main purpose of Human Resources?",
    "answer": "responsible for all aspects of managing individuals who  work within a business",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the main purpose of Marketing?",
    "answer": "responsible for identifying the needs and wants of business  customers and developing products/services to meet those  needs",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the main purpose of Operations?",
    "answer": "organising the process that turns inputs into  outputs/finished goods that can be sold to customers",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What is the main purpose of Finance?",
    "answer": "managing the financial resources in a small business and  reporting on financial performance",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main activities of Human Resources?",
    "answer": "Recruitment and selection of employees  <br />Training and development of employees  <br />Performance management of employees  <br />Responsibility for health and safety in the workplace  <br />Ensuring compliance with employment legislation",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main activities of Marketing?",
    "answer": "Market research, i.e. to research the market and find out customer opinions  <br />Developing a marketing mix: Product, Price, Place, Promotion (4Ps)",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main activities of Operations?",
    "answer": "Production planning<br />Producing the product or service<br />Quality control<br />Stock control<br />Logistics",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "What are the main activities of Finance?",
    "answer": "Organisation and allocation of financial resources<br />Financial performance reporting<br />Monitoring of cash flow",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  },
  {
    "Question": "When a business starts up all activities may be carried out by the same person.  Explain the limitations of this.",
    "answer": "When a business starts up there will be a lot of demands on the time of the entrepreneur. However, they  are unlikely to have sufficient finance to employ experts to take responsibility for some of the tasks. They  will therefore do them all themselves despite lacking skills. This can create stress as well as meaning that  tasks are not done to the correct standard. This could affect the business’ ability to survive.",
    "Topic": "LO6 - Different functional activities needed to support a business start-up",
    "subtopic": ""
  }
]